Where's your father?
你父親人呢？
Here you go.
請用
Hey.
嗨
It's me, Mutchy!
我是阿睦喔！
How was he able to come?
他是怎麼過來的？
Move aside!
閃開！
Future, here I come!
我要去未來了！
Wait for me, Junko!
給我等著，純子！
Unclog your ears.
你要平衡耳壓
Don't forget to unclog your ears.
別忘了耳壓的問題
Anyway, that's how…
總之事情就是這樣
I, Mutchy, made it to Tokyo in 2024 all the way from 1986.
本大爺阿睦從1986年 來到了2024年的東京
As proof,
為了留下證明
I left my autograph on the wall.
我還在牆上簽了名
I think it should be "from."
英文要寫“來自”才對吧？
Anyway, you really do look like me.
話說你跟我長得還真像耶
My son,
兒子啊
come here.
來坐在我旁邊
Don't be so tense.
別這麼緊張嘛
Come on, you.
你這小子真是的
Take a photo of us.
幫我們拍張照
You've got one of those sleek gadgets, right?
你有那個光滑的東西吧？
Uh, okay.
這個嘛，我是有啦
Yo, future people!
喲，未來人！
Say cheese.
笑一個
So, where's Junko?
所以純子在哪？
She departed on the 5 a.m. bus this morning.
她搭今天早上五點的公車回去了
Huh?
不會吧？
Junko?
純子？
Hey, long time no see.
是你們啊，好久不見
Why are you dressed all cutesy?
你怎麼了？還裝可愛，穿成這樣
Mutchy was looking for you.
阿睦學長一直在找你喔
We won tickets to be in the audience for Yan Yan Utau Studio.
我收到中獎明信片
-You'll join us, right? -Uh…
-你也會去吧？ -那個…
Well, I'm not interested in stuff like that anymore.
不，我已經對那種事沒興趣了
Bye!
再見囉
What?
什麼？
TSUNETA CRAM SCHOOL
（常田補習班）
My ears still feel a little blocked.
總覺得耳朵還是有點痛
Huh? She went back?
啥？她回去了？
That's right.
就是這麼一回事
Give me a break.
開什麼玩笑？
If Junko isn't here, why did I come to the future?
如果純子不在，我到未來根本沒意義
If you truly traveled through time here, that is.
那也要是你真的穿越了時空
What did you say?
你說什麼？
Do you…
我問你
seriously believe this is 2024?
你是真的相信現在是2024年嗎？
It isn't?
難道不是嗎？
What? Then who is he?
不會吧？那這傢伙是誰？
Are you familiar with doppelgangers?
你有聽過“分身”嗎？
D…
分…
Doppel…?
分身？
In this world,
在這世界上
there are three individuals who share the same face as you, including yourself.
跟自己長得一樣的分身 包含自己在內共有三人
And this man is one of them.
他就是其中一人
He's your doppelganger.
也就是你的分身啊
Doppel…
分身…
Doppelgangers don't have an identity.
分身沒有自己的意志
They're like mirrored reflections of you.
是有如鏡中人般的存在
What? Stop it.
幹嘛？別學我啦
You're creeping me out.
噁心死了
What's your favorite vehicle? Three, two, one.
喜歡的交通工具是什麼？ 你們同時回答
-Bikes.
-機車
"Our matching…"
“成雙成對的…”
-"Sneakers."
-“運動鞋”
This is freaky.
太可怕了
Those who encounter their doppelgangers experience their bodies deteriorating,
遇到自己分身的人肉體會立刻被侵蝕
and eventually…
最終…
they die.
會導致你死亡
You're lying!
你騙人！
I don't feel sick at all.
我的身體沒有任何問題啊
You're bleeding from your ear.
你的耳朵在流血喔
Here.
給你
We can't afford to let more people know about the time machine!
如果讓更多人 知道時光機的存在會很麻煩！
Dad!
爸爸！
Stay back!
別過來！
This is scary.
嚇死人了…
Mr. Ogawa.
小川先生
How can I help you?
怎麼了嗎？
Um…
請問一下…
Do you know who I am?
你知道我是誰嗎？
No.
不知道耶
Thank goodness.
太好了
They all seem to know you, though.
但他們好像認識你呢
Huh?
什麼？
I'm Takeru Kuramochi,
我是倉持猛
I've been an announcer here for seven years now.
是進公司第七年的主播
EBS TV'S POPULAR ANNOUNCER WHY WAS HE DROPPED?
（EBS電視台大受歡迎的主播 為何會遭冷凍？）
In his first year as an announcer,
他在入職第一年就優於常人
he landed the prime time sports section, an exceptional feat.
以新人主播之姿 負責熱門時段的運動單元喔
He had a great start to his career!
事業原本一帆風順呀！
In his second year, his good looks helped him win the top spot
因為他帥氣的長相 讓他在第二年就登上
in the favorite TV announcer ranking.
最愛的電視主播排名的第一名喔
He's handsome, after all.
畢竟是個帥哥呀
I wonder why we don't see him lately.
最近怎麼都沒看到倉持猛呀？
It's all because of something that happened three years ago.
起因是三年前的某個事件喔
It was that secret affair he had with a female athlete, right?
是他跟女性運動員的 幽會外遇事件吧？
Why did you turn it off?
你為什麼要關掉電視呀？
I accompanied an athlete to her training camp
進行東京奧運的強化集訓時
before the Tokyo Olympics to cover her journey.
我也一同前往採訪
What? The Tokyo Olympics?
什麼？在東京辦奧運？
Three years ago?
三年前？
Damn it. I won't be able to see it.
可惡，那我就看不到了
-And? -Right.
-繼續說吧 -好
I was chosen to be the main presenter for EBS.
我擔任敝公司的主要播報員
It must've been a big step up for you.
你被大力提拔了呀
I commentated on skateboarding.
播報滑板競賽的實況
What? Skateboarding at the Olympics?
什麼？在奧運比滑板？
It became an Olympic sport for the first time in the Tokyo Games.
是的，那從東京奧運 開始成為正式項目
Who did you have an affair with?
你外遇的對象是什麼人呀？
Um…
那個…
Isn't it a little much?
你不時要切換語氣，感覺很慌忙
It is, isn't it?
是啊，你說得對
It's a bit much.
是有一點沒錯啦
I'll shut up for a while.
我稍微安靜一下
Right.
好的
Her name is Seira Kido,
當時我有幸訪問了
an athlete from the street skateboarding whom I got to interview.
一位名叫木戶聖羅的街頭運動選手
Then, I got to send her a DM on social media.
並有幸用社群媒體傳了私訊給她
I got to like her post and got her to follow me.
有幸在她的頁面按讚 她還追蹤了我的帳號
Then, I got her to have a meal with me.
之後有幸跟她一同用餐
And when she got drunk, I got to take her to a hotel.
並有幸把喝醉的她送回飯店
And that night…
就在那晚…
we hooked up.
我們做了
Shouldn't you say you "got some"?
這句卻不加“有幸”啊？
Huh?
什麼？
You should say you "got some."
你該說“有幸做了”才對啊
If anything, that's what you really "got."
說到底那是最幸運的部分吧
I was excited because it was my first business trip,
的確，我因為第一次出差樂昏了頭
and I got some twice.
有幸跟她戰了兩回合
I didn't ask how many times.
我又沒在問你次數
So, how did they find out?
然後呢？怎麼會被發現？
Were there photos?
不小心被拍到了嗎？
-These are photos from that time. -Hey, that's enough!
-這是那時候的照片喔 -等一下，別看了！
Funny how they didn't notice someone taking photos of them so close.
這麼近距離被拍也沒察覺到呀
He cheated once and ended up losing everything.
因為一次的外遇，他就失去了一切喔
Twice, to be exact.
正確來說是兩次才對喔
That's right.
你說得沒錯
For the duration of the Olympics,
在奧運期間
I was ordered to stay at home.
我被下令要在家中反省
After I was allowed back to the office, I spent two and a half years
在家中反省完後 也都在收集資料或影印劇本
handling assistant duties.
有兩年半都在做助理導播的工作
I regularly submitted written apologies and underwent compliance training.
定期提交反省文 並去上企業規範的課程
I finally finished making amends and was poised for a comeback.
我終於贖了罪，看到復出的機會
But this spring,
不過就在今年春天
the manager of Risk Management changed,
風險管理部的部長卻換了人
putting me back to square one.
我又被打回了原點
So it's you!
是你啊！
That's risky! Pause the video.
有風險！暫停影片
He's not buckled up.
他沒有繫安全帶吧
His outfit blends with the seatbelt, but he's wearing it.
因為衣服是同色系的 很難看出來，但他有繫
If it's not clear, it's not there.
如果看起來沒繫的話，就是沒繫
We need to retake or cut the scene.
看是要重拍還是剪掉
What do you want?
有事嗎？
Your features have changed.
你的容貌好像變了很多耶
Spending all day checking footage and scripts will do that to you.
整天都在確認影片跟劇本 臉就會自然變成這樣啦
Hey, this actor is acting a little hyper. I want a urine test!
我說啊，這演員太亢奮了 叫他去驗尿！
-What? -Yeah.
-什麼？ -嗯
A test?
驗尿嗎？
Mr. Ogawa has a question regarding announcer Takeru Kuramochi.
關於主播部門的倉持猛 他似乎有話要跟你說
Forget it.
不行喔
As long as I'm in this position, he's never making a comeback.
只要我在這職位，他就不能復出
Nagisacchi,
小渚
as of 2024, is committing adultery an illegal offense?
在2024年外遇是犯法的嗎？
It's not a crime.
並不是犯罪行為
Basically, it's a private problem.
所以這是家庭內的問題
It's up to the missus whether to forgive him or not.
要不要原諒，是由妻子決定的吧？
I don't think you guys have the right to judge.
你們應該沒有審判的權利吧？
He's still saying stuff like this.
他還在說這種話呢
Huh?
怎樣？
Are you Mr. Compliance's henchman?
你也是合規部長的手下？
I'm Uryu, the sub-leader of the political correctness
我是瓜生，目前擔任考查部政治正確
and SDGs promotion section of the examination department.
及永續發展目標推廣課的副指導人
Oh? Say that again.
是喔，你再說一次看看
I'd rather not.
不要
Cheating is a sign of man's wealth.
“有出息的男人才能外遇”
Even Hiroshi &amp; Kibo agree.
Hiroshi &amp; Kibo這麼說過
"If you're into unattractive guys, I'll reconsider."
“若你喜歡不受異性歡迎的男人 那我會重新考慮”
Don't be ridiculous.
別說傻話了
Don't defend someone who had an affair.
難道要替外遇的人說話嗎？
I know it's wrong to cheat on your spouse.
搞婚外情是不對的 這種事我也知道啊
But it was just once.
但就只是一次喔
Just one mistake, and you kick him downstairs for three years.
就只是犯錯一次耶 結果他得擔任閒職三年
Relocating and assigning him minimal work is an abuse of authority.
這算是濫用職權進行不當異動 故意交辦過少的業務內容
I say this falls under power harassment.
算是職場霸凌的一種
Wow.
好厲害
I sound like a proper counselor, don't I?
我這樣很有諮商師的樣子吧？
Do I need to repeat myself?
要我再說一次嗎？
It's true that his wife was quick to issue an apology.
他的妻子確實很快就發道歉聲明了
-Is that so? -Yeah.
-是這樣嗎？ -對
She's Yoko@home, a cooking specialist.
妻子是料理研究家 “洋子@home”小姐
She released an apology four hours before news of the adultery leaked.
在他外遇被報導出來的四小時前 就發布了謝罪貼文
I'm sorry my hubby's nibbling caused concern to the public.
這次因為我丈夫偷吃的事情 讓社會大眾擔心了
Don't worry about us.
我們家還是很和樂喔
After all, I have him hooked through his stomach.
因為我有緊緊抓住他的胃
Let's love and eat!
愛與吃真重要！
She doesn't sound upset, but it's still scary.
她明明沒在生氣 卻讓人覺得恐怖吧？
She shared this four hours before the news?
這在四小時前就發布了？
Yeah.
對
It was too early, and people didn't know what she was apologizing for.
因為太早了 大家都不知道她道歉的原因
It's better than being late.
太早總比太晚好
Was it 20 days later that Kuramochi held the apology press conference?
倉持的謝罪記者會 是在20天後才舉行吧？
He apologized while standing up, seated, half-sitting, and at an angle.
他站著道歉、坐著道歉 半蹲道歉、幽默地道歉
I'm truly sorry!
萬分抱歉！
Even after the affair, he and his wife got along,
事情爆出來後夫妻關係也很和睦
and they welcomed their long-awaited first baby last year.
去年他們期待已久的 第一個小孩也出生了
So, the stage is set.
已經做好萬全準備了嘛
All that's left is the hubby's comeback!
剩下的就是丈夫的復出
Mr. Ogawa,
小川先生
don't underestimate the influence of TV.
你可不能太小看電視的影響力啊
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
TV is free, so folks who don't want to watch don't have to!
反正觀眾是看免費節目 不想看的人別看就好了
Why can't you take a firm stance like that?
像這樣強勢一點不好嗎？
Fine, for a trial run,
那就試著讓他去
let's send him to the streets for Asappara Time.
《晨間時光》的街頭外景吧
We did it, Nagisacchi!
成功了耶，小渚！
-Prepare with a boil!
-泡熱水恢復原樣！
Raku Foods' fried rice vermicelli!
樂食的炒米粉！
Good morning.
早安
It's 5:45 a.m.
現在是早上5點45分
It's 11 degrees Celsius outside Shiodome Station.
汐留站前面的溫度是11度
It can be chilly in the morning and evening,
雖然早晚比較涼
so you'll want a light jacket.
需要穿薄外套
But it will warm up around noon and may make you sweat a little.
但白天氣溫升高，會熱到出汗
-Also, the air is dry. -Huh?
-另外，因為空氣乾燥… -什麼？
-It's perfect for drying your laundry. -Wake up, Ichiro!
-是適合曬衣服的日子 -快起來，市郎先生！
My dad! My dad is on TV!
是老爸！老爸上電視了！
-Wake up! -Many people may be planning outings.
-醒醒啊！ -許多人都計劃外出旅行吧
It's me, Mutchy!
我是阿睦喔！
We should have a warm day ahead.
應該會是很暖和的一天
-Back to you in the studio. -Oh, crap!
-那鏡頭交回給攝影棚 -天啊，糟糕！
ASAPPARA TIME
（《晨間時光》）
Morning!
早安…
I missed the program when it aired. How are the reactions?
我沒看到現場直播 大眾的反應如何？
Well,
這個嘛
not too good.
狀況不太好
-Actually, they're the worst. -What?
-可以說是糟透了 -怎麼會？
First, these posts were made on social media.
首先，在社群媒體上有這種貼文
"Hey, did I just see Kuramochi?"
“啥？那是倉持對吧？”
"Is it okay for someone who had an affair with an athlete to appear on TV?
“跟運動員外遇還能上電視喔？”
It's just two people who noticed.
搞什麼？只有兩人收看
These comments were noticed by a content writer
有個網路作家八成是用 “晨間時光”的主題標籤搜尋
who probably searched #AsapparaTime.
看到這些評論
And lazy article number one was written.
未經查證，隨手寫出第一篇報導
"After his affair with a female athlete,
“倉持猛主播在跟女性運動員外遇後
TV announcer Takeru Kuramochi vanished from the spotlight."
就從大眾視野中消失
"He returned to TV after three years, appearing on a morning news show."
卻睽違三年出現在早上的資訊節目”
You could literally write this without leaving your kotatsu.
真的是坐在家中暖爐 就寫得出來的內容
This flimsy article was copied and pasted on social media, where it went viral.
這篇沒營養的報導被人複製轉貼 在社群媒體上被大量轉發
And the content writer quoted excerpts to craft lazy article number two.
網路作家在精選那些內容後 寫了第二篇偷懶的報導
"One of the opinions shared online
“‘看到外遇混蛋的臉 從早上心情就很差’
was, 'Seeing this adultererr ruined my morninng.'"
能‘砍’到‘住’樣的意見”
This article is way too lazy!
就算是沒怎麼用心 也不能寫得如此隨便吧！
Right. Even the typos seem half asleep.
是吧？最後一句還打錯字 能看出他是半睡半醒的狀態
A comment left on this article,
在這篇報導的評論欄
"Isn't it too early for his comeback?" was agreed by 27,000 users.
對“他要復出還太早了吧？” 表示認同的有兩萬七千人
What?!
什麼？
TOTAL: 2 COMMENTS
（投稿：共兩條評論）
None of them watched the program, did they?
這些人根本沒看過節目吧？
Well, I didn't either.
不過我也沒看就是了
"I didn't watch it, but I'm still offended."
“我沒看節目，但太讓人不悅了”
"Never seen this show, but if Kuramochi's on it, count me out."
“我也沒看，但如果倉持要上節目 以後絕不會看，我沒看就是了”
"My husband cheated on me with a married woman."
“我也是被丈夫外遇的妻子 老公的出軌對象也是已婚者
"It's unforgivable, I didn't watch it though."
不可原諒，但我沒看節目”
Do you see now?
這下你懂了吧？
It's not about pleasing the actual viewers.
電視要應付的對象不是觀眾
TV must cater to the nonviewers.
而是沒看的那群人
How does that even work? They're not even tuning in!
要怎麼應付？他們根本沒看啊
That's why it's all pointless.
所以一切都是毫無意義的
Real viewers provide positive feedback,
有看的還算好心
but nonviewers only care about griping and finding faults.
沒看就抱怨的人原本就心懷惡意
That's the reality of bashers.
這就是抨擊名人的實際情況
But…
但是…
people will complain no matter when we bring him back.
不管他什麼時候復出都會有人抱怨
We've got to deal with it sooner or later.
早晚都得下定決心啊
Obviously, it's too soon for that.
明顯不是現在吧？
So, Kuramochi,
我說啊，倉持
if you're on TV,
只要你一上電視
the nonviewers make a fuss.
沒看節目的人就會一片譁然
I'll resign.
我會辭職
I don't want to cause more trouble for everyone.
我不能再給各位添更多麻煩了
I understand, but not just yet.
我能理解，但現在時機不對吧？
I'm Kuhombutsu, the personnel manager.
我是人事部長的九品佛
-What's your name? -Kuramochi.
-你叫什麼名字來著？ -敝姓倉持
Because of you,
因為你的關係
there's about to be a boycott against rice vermicelli.
現在有人發起要拒買米粉
Vermicelli?
米粉？
They're sponsoring Asappara Time.
是《晨間時光》的贊助商
#I_Won't_Buy_Rice_Vermicelli is trending!
“#拒買米粉”的主題標籤 成為熱門話題了
"I used to enjoy the rice vermicelli they advertise on the program
“竟在聘請外遇主播的節目 播米粉的廣告
with that cheating announcer. Too bad."
我原本很喜歡吃，真可惜”
"I wasn't a fan of rice vermicelli to begin with, but now I hate it."
“我本來就不喜歡米粉 但現在變得討厭了”
Well, you won't die not eating it!
不吃米粉又不會死！
-Grandpa! -Huh?
-外公！ -幹嘛？
Sorry.
很抱歉
Soon, our various sponsors will come to our sales department with complaints.
各贊助商應該會在近期 聯絡我們的營業部門抱怨
So, if you want to resign, that would be the time.
如果你心意已定，請在那個時候離職
He doesn't even have the freedom to quit? Hold on!
他連辭職的自由都沒有？等一下
In these times, you need to address scandals in your own company.
現在這個時代 如果連自家公司的醜聞都不碰
Otherwise, people may bash you for being too lenient.
可能會被抨擊說只會看上頭臉色
Let's put together a special on Asappara and interview people on the street.
做個《晨間時光》特輯去街上訪問吧
Don't worry, Kuramochi. You'll make your comeback.
別擔心，倉持，我一定會讓你復出
No, it's fine now.
不用再幫我了
You can't give up.
別放棄啊
If you're never forgiven for making one mistake,
就只是犯錯一次都不能被原諒
this world is messed up!
那樣的社會是不對的！
Just once
只有一次
Just one mis--
僅此一次的過錯…
Um…
奇怪
Just once
只有一次…
Suzuki-kun was sold out.
鈴木同學的賣完了
So I got Sato-kun.
佐藤同學可以嗎？
Thanks.
謝謝你
Take a seat.
隨意坐吧
I think I'll go to school.
我還是去學校好了
Why?
為什麼？
Because staying home
因為我待在家
feels like being in school now.
跟待在學校沒什麼兩樣
No way!
真的假的？
Sako is coming to school?
佐高同學要來學校了？
You did it! You moved mountains!
你做到了耶！成功愚公移山！
It's not confirmed yet.
還不知道結果如何啦
But I didn't want people to be shocked, so I let Mr. Yasumori know.
他突然出現大家會嚇到 所以我有先跟安森老師說
And what did he say?
老師說什麼？
He was pissing everywhere as he said,
他一邊把尿灑來灑去一邊這麼說
"Great job! Thanks, Kiyoshi!"
“幹得好！謝謝你，阿清！”
Uh, this happened in the bathroom.
那個，我是在廁所跟他說的
Say that first.
這種事你要先講啊
You surprised me.
不然我們會嚇到
I'm happy for you, Kiyoshi.
太好了，阿清
Go take a bath.
你先去洗澡吧
Okay.
好
What?
怎麼了？
Did something nice happen over there?
你在那邊碰到了什麼好事嗎？
Why do you ask?
為什麼這麼說？
Because you've come back acting like a good girl.
畢竟你回來後明顯變成了一個乖孩子
Nothing really.
沒發生什麼事啊
I just realized it's better to be seen as cute.
我只是發現當個可愛的女孩比較吃香
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Delinquent girls…
不良少女…
were extinct.
完全消失了
I should've expected that.
這也沒辦法
Dressing like that,
打扮成那模樣
smoking, spitting,
抽菸、吐口水
scowling, and fighting.
到處亂瞪人、吵架
And saying, "It's irritating. It doesn't concern me."
把“焦急萬分，怎樣都沒差” 掛在嘴邊
It's weird.
會顯得很怪啊
I thought being delinquent…
我本來以為當女流氓
was a sign of being rebellious.
是叛逆的一種證明
But rebellion is just…
但說到底，叛逆期啊
a way of seeking attention.
就只是在撒嬌
If you really want to be left alone,
如果真心希望家人丟著自己不管
you should dress like you don't need people to care.
只要穿上能讓對方安心的服裝就好
And when I did…
但真的穿上後…
They didn't leave you alone, did they?
對方沒有放著你不管對吧？
I see.
這樣啊
So something nice did happen.
果然發生了好事
I'm happy for you.
真是太好了
Yeah.
是啊
I'm excited.
充滿了期待
I'm not afraid of getting older anymore.
我不再害怕變老了
I don't know who I'll meet,
未來會認識什麼樣的人？
what job I'll have,
做什麼樣的工作？
or if I'll get married.
會不會結婚？這些我都不知道
But I want to enjoy them all.
不過我都想好好體驗
That's why I'm going to study now.
所以現在要用功念書
Good idea.
說得好
Being a delinquent is a waste of time.
到處作惡太浪費時間了
It really is.
沒錯
Everyone has their own phone.
每個人都拿著一支手機
They can take photos, listen to music, and even board the train with it.
能用來拍照、聽音樂，還能搭電車
And with those, anything you want gets delivered with just one click.
也有這種產品 上網點幾下想要的東西就會送來
It's awesome.
根本就棒透了啊
Maybe delinquents died out because they're less discontent.
可能是因為沒什麼不滿 所以學壞的青少年才會消失
I'm not sure about that.
是這樣嗎？
People are still discontent about things.
我想還是有些不滿吧
My dad…
老爸他啊
is pretty cool.
很了不起
Mr. Ogawa?
你說小川老師？
You think so?
你這麼認為啊？
He's a short-tempered geezer who smells like farts,
他明明那麼愛生氣，放的屁超臭
and who can't even tell C-C-B from Checkers.
連C-C-B跟方格子樂團 都分不清的大叔
But he's keeping up with the future.
竟也順利適應了未來
Not only that, people in the future are counting on him.
不只是這樣，未來人甚至還仰賴著他
I need to work hard too.
我也要加油
Did his adultery
“他的外遇
personally cause you any trouble?
有對你造成實際的困擾嗎？”
DID HIS ADULTERY PERSONALLY CAUSE YOU ANY TROUBLE?
（他的外遇 有對你造成實際的困擾嗎？）
HE DIDN'T DIRECTLY HARM ME, BUT IT'S STILL OFFENSIVE.
（我是沒受影響，但覺得不快）
Could you
“那你敢當著他本人的面 跟他說嗎？”
COULD YOU SAY THAT TO HIS FACE?
（那你敢當著他本人的面 跟他說嗎？）
I COULD, BUT I PREFER NOT TO.
（我敢啊，但我不想說）
You're still here?
你還不回家嗎？
I'm combating slander right now.
我正在對抗誹謗者
Then,
“那麼
I'll come to your house to apologize.
我會去你家道歉”
THEN, I'LL COME TO YOUR HOUSE TO APOLOGIZE.
（那麼我會去你家道歉）
I'D… RATHER YOU DIDN'T.
（不要啊…請饒了我吧）
See? You little…
看吧，你這傢伙…
Are you going to reply to each user?
你打算一個個回覆嗎？
Yeah.
對
I thought you were going to go back with Junko.
我以為你會跟純子一起回去
To Showa? Me?
回昭和？你說我嗎？
Yeah?
這樣啊？
I'm glad you stayed.
雖然你留下來我很開心
But aren't you worried?
但你不擔心嗎？
Junko will be fine without me.
我不在身邊，純子也沒問題的
True.
是啊
Mom is all right.
媽媽沒問題的
We still have nine years.
畢竟還有九年啊
But
但是啊
I feel like this era…
現在這個時代
needs an outsider like me to shake things up.
得混入像我這樣的異物才行
An outsider?
異物？
Yup.
沒錯
Someone inappropriate.
發言極度不妥的人
I need to stick around until the world is a little better.
得多少讓這社會變好一點 包括小渚、秋津
So youngsters like you, Akitsu, and Kuramochi can find happiness.
還有倉持這些年輕人 我想看到你們變得幸福
If I went back to Showa now,
不然即使回昭和
I wouldn't want to contribute to a future like this.
也不會想為這種未來努力工作吧
Here is your order. Please take your drink.
久等了，請拿取飲料
Hey!
喂！
We didn't order that much, you stupid robot!
我可沒點這麼多，你這蠢機器人！
It's fine. We'll finish them anyway.
又沒關係，反正都會喝掉
Go.
你走吧
-Let's toast. -Thank you for your order.
-來乾杯吧 -感謝點餐
-Cheers!
-乾杯！
-Did you watch Hanky-Panky? -Yeah
-你有看《不早睡那檔事》？ -有啊
Did you watch a nip slip?
有不小心露點的場面吧？
Sako!
佐高同學！
-Welcome to Class B, Grade 3!
-歡迎來到3年B班！
Hey!
來…
-Sako!
-佐高…
Tsuyoshi Sato, welcome back!
佐藤強同學，歡迎回來！
It's Sako, not Sato.
不是“佐藤”，是“佐高”
Welcome back!
歡迎回來！
All right!
好！
For the first period,
第一節課
we're running a marathon!
就來跑馬拉松吧！
-Sako!
-佐高…
Sako!
佐高！
You got this!
加油！
Thanks.
謝謝
These are my notes for English.
這是請假期間的英文筆記
And for Classical Japanese.
這是古文的
Thanks.
謝謝
Everyone!
各位！
Let's reach the finish line together!
一起到達終點吧！
Almost there! Go for it.
你快到了！加油！
Sako!
佐高！
-Yeah! -Sako!
-好耶！ -佐高同學！
Sorry. He wants to stay home today.
對不起，他說要請假
I thought I was treating him normally.
我自認是一如往常地對待他
If so, your idea of normal must be off.
如果是這樣，那平時就很有問題了
Sorry.
對不起
You ruined it.
白白浪費了機會
Kiyoshi spent a lot of time to get Sako to open up and yet…
難得阿清花了不少時間 讓佐高同學敞開心胸
-Are you listening? -Sorry.
-你有在聽嗎？ -抱歉
As a parent with a child who skipped school,
如果自己的小孩不去上學
it's like a miracle to see all the other kids
看到其他小孩都去學校
going to school and studying at the same time.
還照著相同課表唸書 會覺得根本就是奇蹟
In fact, it feels abnormal.
不，反倒會認為是異常的
Are you familiar with ASD?
你有聽過ASD嗎？
It's short for autism spectrum disorder.
就是“自閉症類群障礙”
And there's ADHD too,
另外還有ADHD
which stands for attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder,
也就是“注意力不足過動症”
and SLD, specific learning disorder.
簡稱SLD的“特殊學習障礙” 因為這些原因
Kids with these conditions struggle in school and group settings.
無法跟上學校課程 以及團體生活的小孩
And in Showa…
在昭和時代…
I mean, in the present,
也就是現代
they get labeled as truants, lazy, or just not trying hard enough.
在現代會被認定是 單純的偷懶、怠惰、依賴父母
People assume it's a family issue or a lack of willpower that--
被批評沒毅力或是家裡有問題…
What is it?
你是怎樣？
-Did you see? -Yeah. It's her, isn't it?
-你有看到嗎？ -有，是她沒錯吧？
I'm talking about something important.
我正在談論重要的事耶
-That's Kyon Kyon. -Kyon Kyon.
-是Kyon Kyon -Kyon Kyon
Huh?
什麼？
No way.
真的假的？
Her face was tiny!
她的臉真的好小喔！
It was the size of a small paperback.
是可以用文庫本蓋住的大小
I should've asked her for an autograph!
應該跟她要簽名的
Totally! Another opportunity might never--
就是說啊！這種機會 不會再有第二次…
Sorry.
不好意思
Regarding Sako, I'll rethink how I approach him from tomorrow onwards.
關於佐高的事 我會再想想明天以後要怎麼處理
By the way, Sakae, are you free after this?
話說回來，紗加惠小姐 你今天接下來的時間有空嗎？
I am.
有空啊
You promised me
因為今天
you'd take me to that salad bar at the disco in Shinjuku, remember?
本來就跟你約好了 你說要帶我去新宿的沙拉吧舞廳
I'm not feeling it, though.
雖然我沒那個心情就是了
Exactly!
沒錯！
You can eat all the salad you want!
沙拉可以吃到飽喔！
That's the point of a salad bar.
因為是沙拉吧
Let's go.
我們走吧
Here.
來
Thanks.
謝謝
He suddenly started acting strange as we were leaving the bar.
他的情緒忽然異常高昂 就在我們離開店裡的時候…
Ladies first?
女士優先？
I didn't expect you to know that, Sakae.
你懂得真多，紗加惠
It's a dying custom in Europe because it contradicts gender equality.
因為這舉動不符合男女平權 在歐洲是個逐漸式微的文化
But it's Showa 61,
但現在是昭和61年
and it didn't come across as sarcastic.
再加上他的行為不讓人反感
So, it felt casual?
很自然啊？
Exactly!
就是那樣！
He stood in front of me on the way down the escalator, and behind on the way up.
電扶梯往下時他會站前面 往上時他則會站在我後面
He carried my heavy stuff too.
東西很重時他還會幫忙拿
And with his looks, it felt pretty nice having him do that.
再加上他的長相 所以不會讓人覺得不舒服
Did it make you like him?
你可能會喜歡上他喔
I'm not sure about that.
我不確定耶
At the disco, he just kept munching on salad and dancing.
他在迪斯可舞廳裡吃了沙拉後跳舞
Salad and dancing.
吃了沙拉後跳舞
He was like some rabbit, like a tall rabbit.
他難道是兔子嗎？感覺是高大的兔子
Please take the sofa.
請坐靠裡面的位子
Thanks.
謝囉
-He even let me have the comfy sofa. -Thank you.
-他還把鬆軟的沙發讓給我坐 -謝謝
So I asked him.
我就問他
"Why does it come so naturally to you?"
為什麼能自然地做出這些事
My father has always had that mindset.
我父親是有那種觀念的人
Your father?
你父親？
My father is an excellent cook,
家父很會做菜
and he's never been shy about saying, "I love your Mom," in front of us kids.
即使在小孩面前也毫不羞澀 會直接說“爸爸深愛著媽媽”
And he does it all so casually, without sarcasm.
而且非常自然，不會覺得做作
Are you kidding me?
那是怎樣？
That's like Eiji Bando from Kintsuma.
像是《星期五的妻子》中的板東英二
Come and meet my father.
下次請你跟我父親見面
What?
什麼？
Let's have a meal out on the patio.
我們一起在中庭用餐吧
A patio?
中庭？
I've never seen one outside Kintsuma.
是只有在《星期五的妻子》中 看過的那個
His looks are exactly my type, and inside he's like Eiji Bando.
外表完全是我的菜 而且內在還是板東英二
Don't you think he's a fine catch, at the very least?
說得保留一點，他也是個好對象吧？
Guys who only care about their image are the worst.
只在乎自己面子的男人最差勁了
And it reminded me of my ex-husband--
所以我就想起了離婚的前夫…
You went through a divorce?
阿姨有離過婚啊？
Yeah.
是啊
Sorry.
對不起喔
Why are you apologizing?
為什麼要道歉？
Anyway, whenever he got drunk, he'd always get arrogant.
那傢伙只要喝醉 就一副自以為了不起的樣子
I'm a scientist destined to win the Nobel Prize.
我可是有朝一日 會拿到諾貝爾獎的科學家
As the wife of a man who will be remembered in history,
我可是期待你能表現出
I expect you to act in a fitting way.
留名青史的男人的伴侶應有的樣子
I only asked you to switch seats because of the draft.
我只是因為會吹到風 要你跟我換位子而已啊
I just don't feel like I'm being respected with the way you're acting!
從你的態度我感受不到你對我的尊重
Me?
你說我嗎？
Yes.
沒錯
You're too handsome inside.
你的內在帥過頭了
You've got the looks of Eiji Bando,
外表明明是板東英二
but your mindset is like Eiji Okuda!
內在卻是奧田瑛二！
If you don't act more humble, you'll regret it when you grow up.
如果不活得謙虛一點 等到你長大一定會後悔
Um, old lady.
我說啊，阿姨
Old lady?
“阿姨”？
You're a little tough on me sometimes.
阿姨有時候會對我很嚴苛耶
Am I?
我有嗎？
I'm only in junior high,
我還只是國中生
so please go easy on me.
還請你嘴上留情
Inoue…
井上…
OCCUPATION: BEING HOT
（職業是當帥哥）
ANNUAL SALES SURPASSED 100 MILLION
（年銷售額突破一億！）
One hundred million?
“一億”？
Wait, 100 million?
給我等一下，“一億”？
What's your take on Kuramochi's comeback?
對倉持主播復出有什麼想法？
Saying sorry doesn't fix it.
這不是道歉就能解決的問題吧
Absolutely not.
已經無法接受他了
I don't want to see him back on TV.
會覺得不想再看到他
May I?
可以聽我說嗎？
Don't worry.
不用害怕…
Keep the camera rolling.
別停，繼續錄…
Who should he apologize to?
你提到要道歉，是要對誰道歉？
Obviously,
像是…
to the people he's harmed.
因此造成困擾的對象啊
You said sorry to your wife and the skateboarder, right?
你當時有立刻向妻子 跟滑板妹妹道歉吧？
Yes, and they accepted my apology.
有，她們都原諒我了
Crap, it's him.
不妙，是本人耶
If so, don't you think he can make his comeback now?
既然這樣，他復出也沒關係吧？
But the public hasn't forgiven him yet.
但社會還沒原諒他吧？
The public?
“社會”指的又是誰？
Do you mean you two?
是指你們嗎？
I'm really sorry for causing trouble.
造成這樣的騷動，真的萬分抱歉
You don't have to apologize to us… Right?
對我們是不用道歉啦，對吧？
Yeah, we weren't fans to begin with anyway.
是啊，畢竟我們原本就不是你的粉絲
Obviously, no one's actually upset.
沒人是真心在為此生氣吧
In that case, let's put down two votes for yes.
那就請在讓他復出的欄位投下兩票吧
Got two votes.
獲得兩票囉
It's too contrived. We can't broadcast this.
根本是在作秀嘛 這種內容不可能播出啊
I mean, this isn't right!
這件事很莫名其妙啊！
He just wants to do his job, but he needs the public's approval for that?
他只是想平凡地工作 卻需要得到社會大眾的原諒？
Forget about reporting.
你就放棄做報導主播吧
Is there a place for him in entertainment?
讓他到綜藝節目如何？
If he were a comedian, he could get an older comedian to rib him on YouTube
如果是諧星，會請前輩 在YouTube頻道盛大嘲弄
and pave a new path for him.
看能不能找到出路
But TV announcers are company employees, so…
但電視局主播就是上班族啊
If a big-name celebrity were to rib him,
只要請大明星來嘲諷他
wouldn't that send the message that it's okay to do so?
就會營造出一種和諧氣氛吧 大家會覺得“可以開他玩笑啊”
Someone like Sanma.
像是明石家秋刀魚先生
I could do it.
不然就由我來吧
Not you, Yashima. She said Sanma!
她說的不是八嶋，是秋刀魚！
You put me in an economy seat the other day, not that I mind.
前陣子出外景我還是坐經濟艙喔 雖然是沒差啦
Sorry, the budget is a bit tight these days.
真抱歉，最近預算比較緊一點
Four-eyes won't do the trick.
被這個戴眼鏡的嘲弄也沒效果吧
Your wife…
你太太啊
is on PS, right?
有上《優六》吧？
Oh, that's right!
對了，她有上節目！
Yoko's cooking segment just started.
洋子小姐開始拍料理單元了
He should appear on that, nonchalantly.
你就若無其事地上節目吧
What?
什麼？
He should wear matching aprons with his older wife in the kitchen studio
在廚房攝影棚 跟年紀較大的老婆穿著同款圍裙
and say, "Oh, I can't whip up meringue."
然後說“哎呀，我不會做蛋白霜”
Then she'd reply, "Let me." Whip, whip. "Here."
她會回說“讓我來 看我攪拌一下，你看”
"Wow. You're amazing, Yoko!"
“好厲害，真不愧是洋子！”
And they could keep this up for a few years.
這種小單元持續做個兩、三年吧
I like that, four-eyes! Pretty clever!
好主意，四眼田雞！這人真聰明！
Once viewers get used to his clumsy persona,
你笨拙角色的設定 將會滲透到各觀眾的家庭中
and memories of his affair have been overwritten,
等外遇的記憶被蓋過去
he can nonchalantly return by commentating for a long-distance relay race.
自然地在驛傳接力賽轉播等場合 復出就行了
That will never happen.
完全不可行
-Why not?
-為什麼？
Impression management can't overwrite memories.
即使以角色設定操作人心 也不會讓記憶被洗掉
It just adds another layer.
只會改變層次
Layer?
層次？
Like a level.
也就是“階層”
If anyone brings up his affair, it'll be back to that phase.
若有人把外遇這件事搬出來 就會被打回相同局面
Phase is like a period.
“局面”，也就是“階段”的意思
Yesterday's affair will receive bashing with the same intensity
不管是昨天的外遇還是十年前的外遇
as one from a decade ago.
都會被大眾以相同的力道抨擊
Bashing, setting an example and imposing social sanctions.
“抨擊”就是殺雞儆猴的社會制裁
Shut up. I get the gist.
閉嘴啦，我大概都能理解
Maybe…
果然…
I really do have to resign.
我是不是只能辭職？
No!
不行！
You can't set this precedent. Never.
絕對不能創下那種先例！
But still…
但是…
If I were a regular person,
如果我不是公眾人物
I wouldn't be receiving this level of backlash.
也不會被罵成這樣
It was just once.
但只犯錯一次耶
A man messes up just once,
面對只走錯一次路的人
and this society won't let him return to his former position.
這社會竟不允許他回到原本的職位
Something's seriously wrong with that!
不管怎麼想都太奇怪了吧！
You know what?
我想到怎麼形容了
It's not tolerant at all.
那樣完全是不予寬容嘛！
Even in mah-jongg, beginners' mistakes are forgiven.
就連打麻將都會原諒初學者的犯規耶
That's tolerance, isn't it?
那才叫寬容吧？
It's the same for regular people.
即使是一般大眾也一樣
What?
你說什麼？
Kuramochi, how about dinner tomorrow night?
倉持，你明天晚上 要不要一起吃晚餐？
Mr. Ogawa, you're welcome to join us.
小川先生也請一起來
-Hello. Come in. -Hello.
-你們好，請進 -你好
I'm sorry. My husband is a bit occupied right now.
不好意思，我先生正在忙
Hey! Come in!
嗨！歡迎你們來！
Kayo, watch over the bouillabaisse.
佳代，你去替我看看馬賽魚湯
Don't just stand there! I'll introduce you to everyone.
快點進來啊！我來幫你們介紹
-Enjoy! -Huh?
-很有意思喔！ -不會吧？
He didn't have that furrow here.
他的眉毛沒有皺在一起耶
Yeah.
是啊
All right, everyone. Attention, please!
各位，請注意這邊！
This is my company's announcer Kuramochi
他們是敝公司主播部門的倉持
and our counselor…
以及諮商師…
Hi, I'm Ichiro Ogawa.
大家好，我是小川市郎
I've brought wine.
我買了葡萄酒
Thank you so much.
謝謝你
We've been friends since kindergarten, and we've brought our husbands and kids
這是在佳代跟栗田的結婚紀念日
She's Pocky.
她是百奇
She used to be as thin as a Pocky stick.
因為她以前瘦得像百奇巧克力棒
Now I'm like a Chocoroom.
我現在是蘑菇山啦
That's funny.
真幽默
I'm Takashima, her husband.
我是她老公，敝姓高島
Third-generation director at a cosmetic surgery clinic.
我是千葉傳了三代的 美容外科醫院的院長
This is Taiko.
這位是態子
Her real name is Taeko,
雖然她的本名是妙子
but she caught a pervert on her way to school in junior high.
她國中時在上學途中抓住了一個變態
Stop it. It's embarrassing.
別說了啦，真讓人害羞
We took "tai" from hentai and call her Taiko.
所以就從“變態” 取“態”這個字，有“態子”的綽號
And I'm hentai Taiko's husband, Hiratsuka.
我是“變態”的態子的丈夫 敝姓平塚
I'm an architect.
是名建築師
This feels like something straight out of Kintsuma.
總覺得這氛圍像是《星期五的妻子》
Guess you don't know.
你們沒看過吧？
Shall we head out to the patio?
我們到中庭去吧
Patio!
中庭！
I've never seen one outside of Kintsuma!
我從來都沒在 《星期五的妻子》以外的地方看過！
That's right.
真的
Really?
是這樣啊？
So you were a junior high school teacher and got recruited?
原本是國中老師卻被企業招聘？
The folks at the TV station are a lot like junior high school kids.
因為電視局的那些人 就跟國中生沒兩樣啦
Hey, Kurita,
我問你，栗田
where are you off to?
你要去哪裡？
It's getting chilly, so I thought I'd grab a blanket.
因為變涼了，我想去拿些毯子
Just sit down.
先不用，坐下吧
Come sit.
你就坐下吧
Right.
我知道了
Anyway, Mr. Kurita's personality at home
話說回來啊
is totally different from his office persona.
栗田先生在公司跟在家 給人的感覺截然不同耶
You're aware, right?
你有自覺吧？
This is your 20th wedding anniversary.
知道20周年的結婚紀念日
You know what that means.
代表的是什麼吧
Of course.
我知道
It's been 17 years…
從那件事發生後
since that occasion.
過了17年
That occasion?
“那件事”？
That sounds a bit flippant.
聽起來很隨便呢
Let it go, Pocky. It's all in the past.
算了啦，百奇，都是過去的事了
I've been telling her too.
我也有跟她說過
-It's been 17 years already. -There's no such thing as "already."
-畢竟都已經過了17年 -這種事永遠都不會過去
What's going on?
怎麼了？
What's all this about?
出了什麼事？
-Say, Kuramochi. -Yes?
-倉持，你啊… -是
You cheated on your wife, right?
外遇了對吧？
Uh…
這個嘛…
Yes.
是的
Did Kurita say anything to you about that?
針對這件事 栗田前輩有對你說什麼嗎？
He's been giving me a stern talking-to.
他大力斥責並要我努力
It took him a while to admit it when he did it himself though.
自己那時卻遲遲沒承認
Just let it go already.
別提了啦
See? You've shocked Mr. Ogawa.
你們看，小川先生嚇到了
I think I get the gist.
我大概搞懂是什麼狀況了
Shall we head inside?
要進去裡面嗎？
It's fine.
不用
The kids understand.
孩子們也都懂
It was such a mess.
當時事態很嚴重
Kayo was so upset, poor thing.
佳代整個人都慌了
Oh, yes.
就是說啊
She found out he was having an affair with her childhood friend, Hitomi.
畢竟她得知了外遇對象 是兒時好友的仁美
My bad.
真是抱歉
Ever since then, we two couples gather every year
從那之後我們這兩對夫妻 每年都會像這樣聚在一起
to make sure Mr. and Mrs. Kurita are getting along.
確認栗田夫婦感情圓滿成了常態
You won't slip up this year, will you, Kurita?
今年沒問題吧？栗田
They say some people
畢竟演藝圈啊
in the entertainment industry sleep their way up, you know.
似乎有陪睡之類的事啊
That will never happen.
沒有那種事啦
My wife has forgiven me,
內人也已經原諒我了
and you guys can rest assured I'll never make that mistake again.
沒問題的，我不會再犯那種錯了
Are you kidding me?
你在說什麼啊？
Kayo might've forgiven you, but we will never forgive your betrayal!
就算佳代原諒你了 我們可沒有原諒那種背叛行為
Mr. Kurita, it seems you're not getting it at all.
栗田先生，你果然什麼都不懂
No amount of apologies can erase what you've done.
不管再怎麼道歉 你做過的事都不會消失
It will never fix Kayo and Hitomi's friendship.
佳代跟仁美的感情永遠無法修復
One can never be zero.
一是無法變回零的
I thought you understood that much, at least.
我還想說你好歹也該明白了
Guess we'll have to check on you again next year.
看來我們明年還是得來
I can't forgive you for acting so carefree when you've hurt our dear friend.
竟傷害了重要的摯友 我無法原諒嘻皮笑臉的你
You're integrating into society, reprimanding your subordinates,
還敢融入社會，對下屬說教
and cracking jokes. It's unforgivable!
在那邊說笑話，不可原諒
That's why I don't even watch TV.
所以很抱歉，我不會看電視
Revolting.
真噁心
What did you say?
你說什麼？
Nothing.
沒事
This is the public, huh?
這就是社會大眾啊？
Go on, apologize.
來，快道歉啊
Let it go, Pocky.
夠了啦，百奇
Apologize.
你就道歉吧
To Kayo
對佳代…
and Hitomi.
還有仁美
I never imagined they had invited her.
沒想到他們也有請仁美小姐來
Yeah.
是啊
They didn't introduce her,
因為都沒有介紹她
so I assumed she was a housekeeper.
我還以為她是幫傭
She was the one he cheated with?
沒想到竟是外遇對象
Kayo
佳代
and Hitomi,
以及仁美小姐
I'm truly sorry.
真的萬分抱歉
For crying out loud,
真是的
you better not do it again.
拜託你饒了我們吧
Unbelievable.
真是不敢置信
It all felt staged too.
她們像是在演戲呢
It seemed like they were high on themselves.
感覺她們是在自我陶醉
But…
但是…
I don't know if I should say this.
這種事可以說嗎？
Spill it.
說出來啊
These people…
那些人…
It's none of their business.
根本不關他們的事吧？
It's none of their business!
完全無關！
They're no different from the random people who comment online!
他們跟毫不相關 卻留下評論的傢伙一樣！
They dug up the past, made a fuss, and intimidated the husband.
把往事翻出來，大吵大鬧 還順便對丈夫施加壓力
And afterward, the wife
接著就是妻子…
had this triumphant smile.
帶著優越感的笑容
All right, how about dessert?
那我們來吃甜點吧
It was so scary!
太嚇人了！
Mr. Kurita understands the mindset of online bashers better than anyone else.
正因為栗田先生比任何人 都要了解抨擊他人的群眾心理
That's why he's perfect for the role of Risk Management manager.
才適合擔任風險管理部長啊
Have you ever cheated on your wife, Mr. Ogawa?
小川先生從沒外遇過嗎？
No.
沒有
Actually,
不對
yes.
有
-Huh? -No, yes.
-什麼？ -沒有，有
-No.
-有嗎？ -沒有
Which is it?
到底是哪一個？
It was in my third year of our marriage.
那是我結婚第三年的事
I must've thought that unless I had an affair,
我當時大概是覺得都沒有外遇過
I'm home!
我回來了！
Welcome back!
你回來了啊！
Yuri, one of my buttons is coming loose.
百合，這件釦子快要掉了
Leave it right there.
把衣服放在那邊
Okay.
好
I pretended to be having an affair.
我偽造了外遇的證據
Or rather, I fabricated evidence.
算是捏造吧
I'll never forget my wife's reaction.
她那時的反應我永遠不會忘
After that, I was too scared to ever cheat on her.
看到那種反應後 我怕到根本不敢外遇
It's not what it looks like!
不是你想的那樣…
Look, Yuri.
百合，你看
It's April 1st.
4月1日
April 1st?
4月1日？
It's April Fool's Day!
愚人節！
All Fool's Day!
4月傻瓜！
Anyway, I didn't cheat on you. It's just a joke!
總之我沒有外遇，只是個玩笑！
-I'll stab you! -Huh?
-我會把你刺死！ -什麼？
If you cheat on me, I'll stab you and kill myself!
你敢外遇的話 我就用這個刺你，然後一起死！
I didn't cheat on you.
我沒有外遇…
-You really didn't? -I didn't.
-沒有嗎？ -沒有
-Are you telling the truth? -I am.
-真的沒有嗎？
Thank goodness!
太好了！
Sorry for doing something stupid
做出這種傻事，真是對不起
I don't know what came over me
都怪我一時心生歹念
Me cheating is a sad lie
外遇只是悲傷的謊言
Payappa Pappa
帕呀帕，帕帕
Sorry for doing something stupid
做出這種傻事，真是對不起
I was just so upset
我一時驚慌失措
If you cheat on me, I'll kill myself
如果你外遇的話，我就死給你看
Pappappa Yappa
帕帕帕呀帕
If it's just once
一次就好
Go easy on me
睜一隻眼閉一隻眼吧
Even if you say sorry
即便你道歉
Pappappa Yappapa
帕帕帕呀帕
I'll never forgive you
我也不會原諒你
Payappa Yappa Yappa
帕呀帕呀帕呀帕
Yuri.
百合
Ichiro.
市郎
After all
畢竟…
The two of us are celebrating
-我們兩人是
Our third April's Fools Day
-第三年的4月傻瓜
Pappappa Yappa Pappaya
帕帕帕呀帕，帕帕呀…
Pappa Payappa
帕帕帕呀帕
Sorry for doing something stupid
做出這種傻事，真是抱歉
I don't know what came over me
都怪我一時心生歹念
If you appear docile,
如果一副溫順的樣子
they'll criticize you for being tiresome.
會被罵說無趣
If you joke about the commotion,
把外遇事件當話題
they'll criticize you for being arrogant.
又會被罵說在得意忘形
No matter what you do, they'll slam you.
不管怎麼樣都會被罵
I'm already stuffed!
我已經吃飽了！
This is the world
你跟我活著的
you and I live in.
就是那樣的世界
Keep that in mind.
千萬要記住這一點
It's sour, rich, and delicious.
帶著酸味又有層次，很好吃
Please try at home.
請務必在家裡做做看
It was just once.
就只是犯錯一次耶
Nowadays, it won't be forgiven.
在這時代就是不行
Three shiitake mushrooms,
需要用上三個香菇
Thirty grams of bamboo shoots, two tomatoes…
30公克的竹筍以及兩個番茄…
Okay.
我明白了
One tablespoon of potato starch dissolved in water.
讓一大匙的片栗粉溶於水
Two tablespoons of black vinegar and chili oil…
加入兩大匙的黑醋還有辣油…
Can I help you?
有什麼事嗎？
Are you Kyon Kyon?
你是Kyon Kyon嗎？
I am.
沒錯
No way.
騙人的吧
W-What do you mean?
你是怎樣？
Kyon Kyon is the same age as me.
畢竟Kyon Kyon跟我是同年
Huh?
什麼？
-Huh?
-啥？ -什麼？
That means you're her doppelganger!
也就是說你是分身？
Huh?!
什麼東西？
-What?! -Huh?
-不會吧？ -怎麼了？
What?!
真的假的？
Is that you, Mutchy? What are you doing over here?
你這傢伙是阿睦吧？ 怎麼會到這邊來？
-Look! -Huh?
-快看… -怎麼了？
This lady is Kyon Kyon, but she's not Kyon Kyon!
那阿姨明明是Kyon Kyon卻又不是
Huh? What are you talking about?
啥？你在說什麼啊？
You're right!
真的耶！
It's Kyon Kyon, but not Kyon Kyon!
明明是Kyon Kyon卻又不是
Barkeep, look!
老闆，你看！
-It's Kyon Kyon but-- -What's your problem?
-明明是Kyon Kyon… -你們從剛才起是怎樣？
You've been really rude!
太失禮了吧！
It's Kyon Kyon's doppelganger!
你是Kyon Kyon的分身？
No. Calm down, Mutchy.
不是，你冷靜點，阿睦
Kyon Kyon…
現在…
is 58 now.
Kyon Kyon可是58歲啊
She's like this now.
就是該長這樣
Congratulations on your 40th anniversary.
恭喜你出道滿40年
Thank you very much.
謝謝你
I saw a poster of you
有張海報
on the wall in the toilet.
貼在廁所裡
When I peeled it off,
把它拿掉後
there was this hole.
後面有個洞
And when I climbed through
然後我穿過去後
it was Showa 61.
發現是昭和61年的世界
SHOWA 61 (1986) JANUARY 18TH SATURDAY
（昭和61年，1986年 1月18日星期六）
You're really cute in person.
本人還真可愛
It's not flattering to hear that now.
-你這時才誇我，我也不覺得開心 -別這樣嘛
There he is! There's my dad!
找到了！老爸在這裡！
Stay back, doppelganger!
別過來，分身！
Akitsu, wait outside.
秋津，你去外面
It's all right.
不要緊的
-Calm down. -Stay back!
-你冷靜點 -別過來！
Let's go. No worries.
我們走吧，不用怕喔
Let's step outside.
一起去外面
-Who are you? -It's all right.
-你是誰啊？ -沒事的…
I'm scared!
好可怕！
Are you an actor?
是劇團？
Are you part of an acting troupe?
是劇團的人嗎？
Is this actually the future?
所以這裡是未來嗎？
It is, isn't it?
是未來對吧？
Forget about that. Just watch over Junko!
別管那麼多，你只要看好純子就好！
Wait, I passed my job interview
等等，我面試應徵上了
to become a host.
是男公關的工作
I'm going to straighten my hair and make 100 million.
我會把頭髮燙直 變成能賺一億的男人
Hey!
給我等等！
Open the door!
快打開！
Stop! Hey, open the door!
停下來！喂，快開門！
Bye!
再見囉！
Take care, Dad.
老爸，你要保重喔
Who's this?
這是哪位？
This is my dad.
他是我爸
Hey.
你好
It's been a long time.
好久不見
It's me, Mutchy.
我是阿睦喔
I don't know what to say.
我不知道該說什麼啦
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：黃思為
Let's all go see Junko.
大家一起去見純子吧
This is maternity harassment!
那樣算是孕婦騷擾吧！
O-Outing?
被爆料？
-Unforgivable! -That means I won't have to die.
-我絕不原諒！ -就不用死了？
Junko, help me!
純子學姐，大事不好了！
It made me feel like I could stay in Showa forever.
我會覺得一直留在昭和也不錯
Is this a date?
這是在約會嗎？
You know nothing about my daughter.
你又不瞭解我的女兒
I can't run the time machine anymore.
不能再運行時光機了